
import { MCQ } from '@/lib/types';

export const chapters = [
  "ICT Fundamentals",
  "Components of Computer System",
  "Digital Skills",
  "Algorithmic Thinking",
  "Programming",
  "Digital Citizenship",
  "Entrepreneurship in Digital Age",
];

export const mcqs: Record<string, MCQ[]> = {
  "ICT Fundamentals": [
    { "id": 1, "questionText": "What does ICT stand for?", "options": ["Information and Computer Technology", "Internet and Communication Tools", "Information and Communication Technology", "Integrated Computer Technology"], "correctAnswer": "Information and Communication Technology" },
    { "id": 2, "questionText": "After completing Unit 1, students should be able to define ICT and what else?", "options": ["Types of computer networks", "Computer", "Advanced programming concepts", "Artificial intelligence"], "correctAnswer": "Computer" },
    { "id": 3, "questionText": "Information refers to:", "options": ["Processed form of data", "Raw facts", "Unstructured text", "Numerical figures only"], "correctAnswer": "Processed form of data" },
    { "id": 4, "questionText": "Which of the following is an input device?", "options": ["Monitor", "Printer", "Keyboard", "Speaker"], "correctAnswer": "Keyboard" },
    { "id": 5, "questionText": "What is data according to the sources?", "options": ["Processed information", "Raw collection of facts and figures", "Output from a computer", "Information stored in memory"], "correctAnswer": "Raw collection of facts and figures" },
    { "id": 6, "questionText": "A computer system includes which two main components?", "options": ["Monitor and Keyboard", "Printer and Scanner", "Hardware and Software", "CPU and RAM"], "correctAnswer": "Hardware and Software" },
    { "id": 7, "questionText": "Software is a set of instructions, data, or program used to:", "options": ["Build computer hardware", "Operate a computer and perform specific tasks", "Connect computers in a network", "Manufacture computer parts"], "correctAnswer": "Operate a computer and perform specific tasks" },
    { "id": 8, "questionText": "Who is known as the father of computer?", "options": ["Alan Turing", "Charles Babbage", "Bill Gates", "Steve Jobs"], "correctAnswer": "Charles Babbage" },
    { "id": 9, "questionText": "Which type of software is designed to run a computer's hardware and application programs?", "options": ["Application Software", "Driver Software", "System Software", "Utility Software"], "correctAnswer": "System Software" },
    { "id": 10, "questionText": "What is an example of System Software?", "options": ["Microsoft Word", "Google Chrome", "Operating System", "Adobe Photoshop"], "correctAnswer": "Operating System" },
    { "id": 11, "questionText": "Application software is a type of computer program or software package that performs:", "options": ["System operations", "Specific functions for a user", "Hardware diagnostics", "Network management"], "correctAnswer": "Specific functions for a user" },
    { "id": 12, "questionText": "Microsoft Word and Excel are examples of:", "options": ["System Software", "Driver Software", "Application Software", "Utility Software"], "correctAnswer": "Application Software" },
    { "id": 13, "questionText": "Driver software is also known as:", "options": ["Application driver", "System driver", "Device driver", "Network driver"], "correctAnswer": "Device driver" },
    { "id": 14, "questionText": "Computer hardware represents the:", "options": ["Software programs", "User interfaces", "Physical and tangible components of a computer", "Operating system"], "correctAnswer": "Physical and tangible components of a computer" },
    { "id": 15, "questionText": "Which of these is a part of computer hardware?", "options": ["Microsoft Windows", "Adobe Photoshop", "Monitor", "Google Chrome"], "correctAnswer": "Monitor" },
    { "id": 16, "questionText": "What is the main function of a System Unit?", "options": ["Displaying output", "Printing documents", "Contains components to process and temporarily store data and instructions", "Connecting to the internet"], "correctAnswer": "Contains components to process and temporarily store data and instructions" },
    { "id": 17, "questionText": "Peripherals are hardware devices used for:", "options": ["Internal processing", "Input, secondary storage and display etc.", "Software development", "Network security"], "correctAnswer": "Input, secondary storage and display etc." },
    { "id": 18, "questionText": "The first generation of computers (1940 to 1955) used:", "options": ["Transistors", "Integrated Circuits", "Vacuum tubes", "Microprocessors"], "correctAnswer": "Vacuum tubes" },
    { "id": 19, "questionText": "UNIVAC-1 and EDVAC are examples of:", "options": ["Second generation computers", "Third generation computers", "Fourth generation computers", "First generation computers"], "correctAnswer": "First generation computers" },
    { "id": 20, "questionText": "The second generation of computers (1957-1963) used:", "options": ["Vacuum tubes", "Transistors", "Integrated Circuits", "Microprocessors"], "correctAnswer": "Transistors" },
    { "id": 21, "questionText": "COBOL and FORTRAN programming languages were used in which computer generation?", "options": ["First Generation", "Second Generation", "Third Generation", "Fourth Generation"], "correctAnswer": "Second Generation" },
    { "id": 22, "questionText": "The third generation of computers (1964 to 1971) used:", "options": ["Transistors", "Vacuum tubes", "Integrated Circuits (IC)", "Microprocessors"], "correctAnswer": "Integrated Circuits (IC)" },
    { "id": 23, "questionText": "IBM-360 series and The Honeywell-6000 series are examples of:", "options": ["First generation computers", "Second generation computers", "Third generation computers", "Fourth generation computers"], "correctAnswer": "Third generation computers" },
    { "id": 24, "questionText": "The fourth generation of computers (1971-1980) introduced:", "options": ["Transistors", "Integrated Circuits", "Vacuum tubes", "Microprocessors"], "correctAnswer": "Microprocessors" },
    { "id": 25, "questionText": "C, C++ and Java were the programming languages used in which generation?", "options": ["Second Generation", "Third Generation", "Fourth Generation", "Fifth Generation"], "correctAnswer": "Fourth Generation" },
    { "id": 26, "questionText": "Fifth generation computers are utilized since 1980 and continue to be used till now, focusing on:", "options": ["Transistor technology", "Integrated circuits", "Artificial intelligence", "Vacuum tubes"], "correctAnswer": "Artificial intelligence" },
    { "id": 27, "questionText": "Which of the following is an ICT device?", "options": ["Television", "Radio", "Printer", "Refrigerator"], "correctAnswer": "Printer" },
    { "id": 28, "questionText": "Which of the following is an example of an ICT device?", "options": ["Washing machine", "Microwave oven", "Storage Devices", "Toaster"], "correctAnswer": "Storage Devices" },
    { "id": 29, "questionText": "ICT is used in almost every field of life, such as:", "options": ["E-Commerce", "Traditional farming", "Manual labor", "Art painting"], "correctAnswer": "E-Commerce" },
    { "id": 30, "questionText": "In communication, ICT can be used to help in:", "options": ["Manufacturing", "Digital communication", "Medical surgery", "Space navigation"], "correctAnswer": "Digital communication" },
    { "id": 31, "questionText": "Newsletters, Posters, Websites, and Multimedia presentations are examples of applications in:", "options": ["Measurement", "Business", "Communication", "Manufacturing"], "correctAnswer": "Communication" },
    { "id": 32, "questionText": "ICT devices are used for monitoring and measuring data in which application?", "options": ["Communication", "Business", "Measurement", "Manufacturing"], "correctAnswer": "Measurement" },
    { "id": 33, "questionText": "GPS system for Weather Forecasting is an example of ICT application in:", "options": ["Communication", "Business", "Navigation", "Manufacturing"], "correctAnswer": "Navigation" },
    { "id": 34, "questionText": "ICT devices have revolutionized the manufacturing industry, leading to:", "options": ["Decreased production", "Increased manual labor", "Increased productivity", "Reduced innovation"], "correctAnswer": "Increased productivity" },
    { "id": 35, "questionText": "Which of the following is an application of ICT in manufacturing industry?", "options": ["Online shopping", "Painting spray cans in car factories", "Video conferencing", "Weather forecasting"], "correctAnswer": "Painting spray cans in car factories" },
    { "id": 36, "questionText": "ICT assists individuals, businesses and organizations in:", "options": ["Decreasing efficiency", "Making business more efficient and effective", "Limiting access to information", "Increasing manual processes"], "correctAnswer": "Making business more efficient and effective" },
    { "id": 37, "questionText": "Which of the following is an advantage of ICT in business?", "options": ["Decreased productivity", "Increased customer complaints", "Better Decision Making", "Mismanagement of resources"], "correctAnswer": "Better Decision Making" },
    { "id": 38, "questionText": "ICT has eliminated the use of:", "options": ["Digital devices", "Paper", "Communication", "Online learning"], "correctAnswer": "Paper" },
    { "id": 39, "questionText": "A web-based LMS (Learning Management System) connects:", "options": ["Machines", "Students, teachers and researchers", "Factories", "Agricultural fields"], "correctAnswer": "Students, teachers and researchers" },
    { "id": 40, "questionText": "One of the disadvantages of ICT devices is:", "options": ["Improved customer services", "Increased productivity", "Misleading and misguided information", "Enhanced data security"], "correctAnswer": "Misleading and misguided information" },
    { "id": 41, "questionText": "A risk to the traditional book and handwriting methods is a disadvantage of:", "options": ["Online learning", "Digital communication", "ICT devices", "Business applications"], "correctAnswer": "ICT devices" },
    { "id": 42, "questionText": "Managing courses online is difficult for:", "options": ["Experienced users", "IT professionals", "Teachers and students", "Computer manufacturers"], "correctAnswer": "Teachers and students" },
    { "id": 43, "questionText": "Which of the following ICT devices is used to display the result of processing?", "options": ["Keyboard", "Mouse", "Scanner", "Monitor"], "correctAnswer": "Monitor" },
    { "id": 44, "questionText": "Charles Babbage is considered the father of computer because he designed the:", "options": ["ENIAC", "UNIVAC-1", "Analytical Engine", "IBM 360"], "correctAnswer": "Analytical Engine" },
    { "id": 45, "questionText": "What kind of communication relies on print media, digital media, and mobile phone?", "options": ["Business communication", "ICT based communication", "Traditional communication", "Measurement communication"], "correctAnswer": "ICT based communication" },
    { "id": 46, "questionText": "What is the purpose of ICT in business based on the source?", "options": ["To replace human workers with robots.", "To solely monitor environmental changes.", "To assist individuals, businesses, and organizations to make business more efficient and effective.", "To limit the flow of information."], "correctAnswer": "To assist individuals, businesses, and organizations to make business more efficient and effective." },
    { "id": 47, "questionText": "In the context of ICT advantages, what does 'Improving customer services' refer to?", "options": ["Only improving physical store experiences.", "Making services digital but less accessible.", "Enhancing the quality and availability of support and interaction for customers through digital means.", "Reducing the need for customer interaction."], "correctAnswer": "Enhancing the quality and availability of support and interaction for customers through digital means." },
    { "id": 48, "questionText": "What is a key characteristic of the 5th Generation Computers?", "options": ["Use of transistors", "Use of integrated circuits", "Focus on Artificial Intelligence (AI)", "Use of vacuum tubes"], "correctAnswer": "Focus on Artificial Intelligence (AI)" },
    { "id": 49, "questionText": "Which ICT application involves data logging, data monitoring, and recording generated during scientific experiments?", "options": ["Environmental Monitoring", "Navigation", "Manufacturing Industry", "Digital Experiments"], "correctAnswer": "Digital Experiments" },
    { "id": 50, "questionText": "What is a 'System Unit' in the context of computer hardware?", "options": ["A printer connected to the computer.", "A monitor displaying information.", "The part that contains the components used to process and temporarily store data and instructions.", "A software program that manages files."], "correctAnswer": "The part that contains the components used to process and temporarily store data and instructions." }
  ],
  "Components of Computer System": [
    { "id": 1, "questionText": "What are the five basic components of a computer system?", "options": ["Monitor, Keyboard, Mouse, Printer, Speaker", "Input Devices, Output Devices, Memory Unit, Control Unit, Arithmetic and Logical Unit", "CPU, RAM, ROM, Hard Drive, USB", "System Software, Application Software, Device Driver, Utility Program, Language Translator"], "correctAnswer": "Input Devices, Output Devices, Memory Unit, Control Unit, Arithmetic and Logical Unit" },
    { "id": 2, "questionText": "What is the main function of Input Devices?", "options": ["To display output", "To store data permanently", "To feed data into the computer", "To process information"], "correctAnswer": "To feed data into the computer" },
    { "id": 3, "questionText": "Which of the following is an input device used to enter data by pressing keys?", "options": ["Mouse", "Keyboard", "Scanner", "Joystick"], "correctAnswer": "Keyboard" },
    { "id": 4, "questionText": "How many types of keyboards are mentioned in the source for traditional typewriters?", "options": ["One", "Two", "Three", "Four"], "correctAnswer": "Two" },
    { "id": 5, "questionText": "What is the primary function of a Mouse?", "options": ["To print documents", "To scan images", "Pointing device to control the cursor position", "To record audio"], "correctAnswer": "Pointing device to control the cursor position" },
    { "id": 6, "questionText": "Which input device uses a laser beam to detect movement?", "options": ["Joystick", "Light Pen", "Scanner", "Mouse"], "correctAnswer": "Mouse" },
    { "id": 7, "questionText": "A joystick is primarily used for:", "options": ["Typing text", "Controlling the cursor position on a monitor screen in games", "Scanning documents", "Recording sounds"], "correctAnswer": "Controlling the cursor position on a monitor screen in games" },
    { "id": 8, "questionText": "What is a Light Pen used for?", "options": ["Playing games", "Selecting a menu item or drawing pictures on the monitor screen", "Scanning barcodes", "Recognizing characters"], "correctAnswer": "Selecting a menu item or drawing pictures on the monitor screen" },
    { "id": 9, "questionText": "What is the main function of a Scanner?", "options": ["To display images", "To print documents", "To capture images and convert them into digital form", "To process sound"], "correctAnswer": "To capture images and convert them into digital form" },
    { "id": 10, "questionText": "What is a Microphone primarily used for in a computer?", "options": ["Outputting sound", "Controlling cursor", "Inputting sound", "Scanning documents"], "correctAnswer": "Inputting sound" },
    { "id": 11, "questionText": "OCR stands for:", "options": ["Optical Character Recognition", "Output Control Register", "Online Command Reader", "Object Color Recognition"], "correctAnswer": "Optical Character Recognition" },
    { "id": 12, "questionText": "What is the purpose of an Optical Character Reader (OCR)?", "options": ["To read barcodes", "To input device used to read text from hardcopy to make it editable", "To scan images", "To recognize human speech"], "correctAnswer": "To input device used to read text from hardcopy to make it editable" },
    { "id": 13, "questionText": "Bar Code Reader is an input device used for:", "options": ["Scanning photos", "Reading bar coded data", "Recording audio", "Controlling games"], "correctAnswer": "Reading bar coded data" },
    { "id": 14, "questionText": "Sensors are input devices that record data about the physical environment. Which of these is a type of sensor mentioned?", "options": ["Temperature Sensor", "Magnetic Field Sensor", "Speed Sensor", "Chemical Sensor"], "correctAnswer": "Temperature Sensor" },
    { "id": 15, "questionText": "What are the two types of monitors mentioned?", "options": ["LED and OLED", "CRT and Flat-Panel", "Plasma and LCD", "IPS and TN"], "correctAnswer": "CRT and Flat-Panel" },
    { "id": 16, "questionText": "Which type of monitor is also known as a Video Display Terminal (VDT) or a Video Display Unit (VDU)?", "options": ["Flat-Panel Display", "LCD Monitor", "CRT Monitor", "SMD LED Screen"], "correctAnswer": "CRT Monitor" },
    { "id": 17, "questionText": "Flat Panel Display units use what to display images?", "options": ["Cathode ray tube", "Thin panel design", "Vacuum tubes", "Magnetic fields"], "correctAnswer": "Thin panel design" },
    { "id": 18, "questionText": "What does SMD stand for in SMD LED Screen?", "options": ["Single Module Device", "Surface Mounted Device", "Smart Mobile Display", "Standard Monitor Device"], "correctAnswer": "Surface Mounted Device" },
    { "id": 19, "questionText": "A Multimedia projector is a high resolution, full-color projector capable of projecting:", "options": ["Only text documents", "Images, video and audio content", "Spreadsheets", "Simple graphics"], "correctAnswer": "Images, video and audio content" },
    { "id": 20, "questionText": "What is a Plotter used for?", "options": ["Displaying video", "Printing vector graphics, architectural drawings", "Scanning documents", "Playing audio"], "correctAnswer": "Printing vector graphics, architectural drawings" },
    { "id": 21, "questionText": "Which output device prints text documents, images, or a combination of both?", "options": ["Plotter", "Monitor", "Speaker", "Printer"], "correctAnswer": "Printer" },
    { "id": 22, "questionText": "A Speaker is an output device that connects to a computer to generate:", "options": ["Images", "Text", "Sound", "Video"], "correctAnswer": "Sound" },
    { "id": 23, "questionText": "What are the three major components of the Central Processing Unit (CPU)?", "options": ["RAM, ROM, Hard Drive", "Input, Output, Storage", "Memory Unit, Control Unit, Arithmetic and Logical Unit", "Keyboard, Mouse, Monitor"], "correctAnswer": "Memory Unit, Control Unit, Arithmetic and Logical Unit" },
    { "id": 24, "questionText": "What is the CPU often known as?", "options": ["The Heart of Computer", "The Eyes of Computer", "The Brain of Computer", "The Storage of Computer"], "correctAnswer": "The Brain of Computer" },
    { "id": 25, "questionText": "What does the Memory Unit do?", "options": ["Processes data", "Controls input/output", "Refers to the amount of data that the memory can hold", "Performs arithmetic operations"], "correctAnswer": "Refers to the amount of data that the memory can hold" },
    { "id": 26, "questionText": "What are the two basic types of computer memory?", "options": ["RAM and ROM", "Primary memory and Secondary memory", "Input memory and Output memory", "Permanent memory and Temporary memory"], "correctAnswer": "Primary memory and Secondary memory" },
    { "id": 27, "questionText": "RAM stands for:", "options": ["Read Access Memory", "Registered Access Memory", "Random Access Memory", "Real-time Access Memory"], "correctAnswer": "Random Access Memory" },
    { "id": 28, "questionText": "ROM stands for:", "options": ["Random Only Memory", "Read Open Memory", "Read Only Memory", "Real-time Operating Memory"], "correctAnswer": "Read Only Memory" },
    { "id": 29, "questionText": "Which type of memory is volatile and loses data when power is lost?", "options": ["ROM", "RAM", "Hard Disk Drive", "SSD"], "correctAnswer": "RAM" },
    { "id": 30, "questionText": "Which type of memory is non-volatile and retains data even when power is off?", "options": ["RAM", "ROM", "Cache Memory", "Virtual Memory"], "correctAnswer": "ROM" },
    { "id": 31, "questionText": "How many bits are in 1 NIBBLE?", "options": ["1", "2", "4", "8"], "correctAnswer": "4" },
    { "id": 32, "questionText": "How many bytes are in 1 KILOBYTE?", "options": ["1", "1000", "1024", "2048"], "correctAnswer": "1024" },
    { "id": 33, "questionText": "Which of these is a commonly used example of secondary storage?", "options": ["RAM", "ROM", "Hard Disk Drive (HDD)", "CPU Cache"], "correctAnswer": "Hard Disk Drive (HDD)" },
    { "id": 34, "questionText": "Hard disk drive is a secondary storage device used to store data:", "options": ["Temporarily", "Volatile", "Permanently", "Indirectly"], "correctAnswer": "Permanently" },
    { "id": 35, "questionText": "Which of the following is an advantage of Hard Disk Drives?", "options": ["Low capacity", "Slow read/write speed", "Large capacity", "Noisy operation"], "correctAnswer": "Large capacity" },
    { "id": 36, "questionText": "SSD stands for:", "options": ["System Storage Device", "Secure Solid Disk", "Solid State Drive", "Software Storage Device"], "correctAnswer": "Solid State Drive" },
    { "id": 37, "questionText": "Which of the following is an advantage of Solid State Drive (SSD)?", "options": ["Expensive", "Limited life span", "High speed", "Data recovery is impossible"], "correctAnswer": "High speed" },
    { "id": 38, "questionText": "USB Flash Memory is a non-volatile solid state storage device, typically up to:", "options": ["100 GB", "500 GB", "1 TB", "1 TB"], "correctAnswer": "1 TB" },
    { "id": 39, "questionText": "What is the primary function of the Control Unit (CU) within the CPU?", "options": ["To perform arithmetic operations", "To store data", "To manage the entire functioning of the computer system", "To display output"], "correctAnswer": "To manage the entire functioning of the computer system" },
    { "id": 40, "questionText": "What is the role of the Arithmetic and Logical Unit (ALU)?", "options": ["To control input/output operations", "To store data temporarily", "To perform calculations and make logical decisions", "To manage the entire system"], "correctAnswer": "To perform calculations and make logical decisions" },
    { "id": 41, "questionText": "What is the first stage in the working of a computer system?", "options": ["Processing", "Storage", "Input", "Output"], "correctAnswer": "Input" },
    { "id": 42, "questionText": "What happens during the 'Processing' stage of a computer system?", "options": ["Data is stored in RAM", "Data is displayed on monitor", "Input information is transformed into output", "Data is collected from the environment"], "correctAnswer": "Input information is transformed into output" },
    { "id": 43, "questionText": "In which stage of data processing is raw data converted into meaningful information?", "options": ["Data collection", "Data storage", "Data preparation", "Data processing"], "correctAnswer": "Data processing" },
    { "id": 44, "questionText": "Which of the following is an input device?", "options": ["Monitor", "Scanner", "Speaker", "Printer"], "correctAnswer": "Scanner" },
    { "id": 45, "questionText": "What is the purpose of 'Data Storage' in data processing stages?", "options": ["To prepare data for input.", "To display the processed information.", "To save processed data for future use.", "To perform calculations on data."], "correctAnswer": "To save processed data for future use." },
    { "id": 46, "questionText": "Which component is responsible for retrieving information from memory and executing instructions?", "options": ["Memory Unit", "Arithmetic Logic Unit", "Control Unit", "Input Device"], "correctAnswer": "Control Unit" },
    { "id": 47, "questionText": "What is the primary purpose of output devices?", "options": ["To collect data.", "To store data.", "To process data.", "To show the results of processing."], "correctAnswer": "To show the results of processing." },
    { "id": 48, "questionText": "What distinguishes primary memory (RAM) from secondary memory (HDD)?", "options": ["Primary memory is slower.", "Primary memory is non-volatile.", "Primary memory is temporary and volatile, while secondary is permanent and non-volatile.", "Primary memory has larger capacity."], "correctAnswer": "Primary memory is temporary and volatile, while secondary is permanent and non-volatile." },
    { "id": 49, "questionText": "Which statement about USB is true?", "options": ["It is a volatile storage device.", "It is a Plug and Play device.", "It needs drivers to run.", "It has unlimited storage capacity."], "correctAnswer": "It is a Plug and Play device." },
    { "id": 50, "questionText": "What is a Gigabyte (GB) equivalent to in terms of Kilobytes (KB)?", "options": ["1024 KB", "1024 MB", "1024 x 1024 KB", "1024 TB"], "correctAnswer": "1024 x 1024 KB" }
  ],
  "Digital Skills": [
    { "id": 1, "questionText": "What is a word processor primarily used for?", "options": ["Creating multimedia presentations.", "Managing emails.", "To enter, format, save and print text.", "To perform complex calculations."], "correctAnswer": "To enter, format, save and print text." },
    { "id": 2, "questionText": "Microsoft Word is described as a popular word-processing program used mainly for:", "options": ["Playing games", "Streaming videos", "Creating documents, brochures, letters, learning activities, quizzes, tests, and students' homework assignments.", "Editing photos"], "correctAnswer": "Creating documents, brochures, letters, learning activities, quizzes, tests, and students' homework assignments." },
    { "id": 3, "questionText": "To open a new blank document in Microsoft Word, which option should be selected from the File tab?", "options": ["Save", "Open", "Print", "New"], "correctAnswer": "New" },
    { "id": 4, "questionText": "Which part of the Word Processor (MS Word) interface provides a quick access toolbar at the top?", "options": ["Ribbon", "Status Bar", "Title Bar", "Scroll Bar"], "correctAnswer": "Title Bar" },
    { "id": 5, "questionText": "Which formatting option makes the text appear thicker and darker?", "options": ["Italic", "Underline", "Bold", "Font color"], "correctAnswer": "Bold" },
    { "id": 6, "questionText": "To save a file in Word, where can you click the save button?", "options": ["On the Ribbon", "In the status bar", "On the quick access toolbar", "In the document area"], "correctAnswer": "On the quick access toolbar" },
    { "id": 7, "questionText": "Which text alignment option places text equally from both the left and right sides of the page?", "options": ["Left Align", "Right Align", "Center Align", "Justify"], "correctAnswer": "Justify" },
    { "id": 8, "questionText": "Page margins determine the blank spaces that lie on the:", "options": ["Top and bottom of the ribbon.", "Left and right sides of the quick access toolbar.", "Top, bottom, left and right sides of a document.", "Top and bottom of the document only."], "correctAnswer": "Top, bottom, left and right sides of a document." },
    { "id": 9, "questionText": "To insert an image into a Word document, which tab should you use?", "options": ["Home", "Layout", "References", "Insert"], "correctAnswer": "Insert" },
    { "id": 10, "questionText": "What is the keyboard shortcut for 'Cut' in Microsoft Word?", "options": ["Ctrl + V", "Ctrl + C", "Ctrl + X", "Ctrl + P"], "correctAnswer": "Ctrl + X" },
    { "id": 11, "questionText": "Which operation places a duplicate in the Clipboard, but you are not removing it from its original location?", "options": ["Cut", "Paste", "Copying", "Moving"], "correctAnswer": "Copying" },
    { "id": 12, "questionText": "What does the 'Spell check' feature in Word help with?", "options": ["Formatting text", "Inserting images", "Adjusting grammar and spelling errors.", "Creating tables"], "correctAnswer": "Adjusting grammar and spelling errors." },
    { "id": 13, "questionText": "Which of the following is used to create a numbered list?", "options": ["Bullets", "Paragraph spacing", "Text alignment", "Numbering"], "correctAnswer": "Numbering" },
    { "id": 14, "questionText": "What is the purpose of the 'Save As' command in Word?", "options": ["To update the last saved version.", "To save the file with the same name.", "To save a new file and/or preserve the original file (backup file).", "To open a saved file."], "correctAnswer": "To save a new file and/or preserve the original file (backup file)." },
    { "id": 15, "questionText": "To insert a table in Word, which tab should you select?", "options": ["Home", "Layout", "Insert", "Design"], "correctAnswer": "Insert" },
    { "id": 16, "questionText": "What is a Header in a document?", "options": ["Text that appears at the bottom margin.", "Text that appears at the top margin of the Word document.", "Page numbers.", "Footnotes."], "correctAnswer": "Text that appears at the top margin of the Word document." },
    { "id": 17, "questionText": "The Thesaurus is a software tool used in Microsoft Word to look up and find:", "options": ["Grammar errors", "Spelling mistakes", "Synonyms (words with the same meaning) and antonyms (words with the opposite meaning).", "Image suggestions"], "correctAnswer": "Synonyms (words with the same meaning) and antonyms (words with the opposite meaning)." },
    { "id": 18, "questionText": "Which of the following is a primary function of word processors?", "options": ["Performing complex computations", "Managing network connections", "Composing and editing documents", "Creating 3D models"], "correctAnswer": "Composing and editing documents" },
    { "id": 19, "questionText": "What does 'Bcc' stand for in email?", "options": ["Blind Carbon Copy", "Basic Carbon Copy", "Business Carbon Copy", "Black Carbon Copy"], "correctAnswer": "Blind Carbon Copy" },
    { "id": 20, "questionText": "Which email authentication type involves passwords?", "options": ["Multi-factor authentication", "Certificate-based authentication", "Biometric authentication", "Password-based authentication"], "correctAnswer": "Password-based authentication" },
    { "id": 21, "questionText": "POP (Post Office Protocol) is used by email clients to:", "options": ["Send emails.", "Store emails on the server.", "Download emails from the server.", "Manage remote mailboxes."], "correctAnswer": "Download emails from the server." },
    { "id": 22, "questionText": "IMAP (Internet Message Access Protocol) is a standard email retrieval protocol that:", "options": ["Downloads emails to the client and deletes them from the server.", "Stores email messages on a mail server and enables the recipient to view and manipulate them as they were stored locally on their device(s).", "Is responsible for sending emails between clients and servers.", "Only supports text-based emails."], "correctAnswer": "Stores email messages on a mail server and enables the recipient to view and manipulate them as they were stored locally on their device(s)." },
    { "id": 23, "questionText": "SMTP (Simple Mail Transfer Protocol) is the principal email protocol responsible for the:", "options": ["Receiving of emails.", "Storage of emails on the server.", "Transfer of emails between email clients and email servers.", "Downloading of emails."], "correctAnswer": "Transfer of emails between email clients and email servers." },
    { "id": 24, "questionText": "Which is a common platform for electronic mail?", "options": ["Netflix", "Spotify", "Gmail", "YouTube"], "correctAnswer": "Gmail" },
    { "id": 25, "questionText": "What is the first step in creating a new Gmail account?", "options": ["Enter phone number.", "Enter your birthday.", "Click on the drop-down arrow to select gender.", "Open a web browser, go to the gmail.com sign up screen, and select Create account."], "correctAnswer": "Open a web browser, go to the gmail.com sign up screen." },
    { "id": 26, "questionText": "Which step is crucial before sending an email to ensure clarity and correctness?", "options": ["Add attachments.", "Reply to all recipients.", "Proofread every email you send.", "Organize emails using folders."], "correctAnswer": "Proofread every email you send." },
    { "id": 27, "questionText": "What is the benefit of organizing emails using different folders/labels?", "options": ["To make the inbox look cleaner.", "To improve email sending speed.", "To organize email messages, calendars, contacts, and tasks.", "To encrypt email content."], "correctAnswer": "To organize email messages, calendars, contacts, and tasks." },
    { "id": 28, "questionText": "What does a password-based authentication involve?", "options": ["Using a physical certificate.", "Using fingerprints or facial recognition.", "Using a temporary code.", "Entering a confidential string of characters to verify identity."], "correctAnswer": "Entering a confidential string of characters to verify identity." },
    { "id": 29, "questionText": "Which authentication type relies on physical characteristics like fingerprints or facial recognition?", "options": ["Password-based authentication", "Certificate-based authentication", "Biometric authentication", "Token-based authentication"], "correctAnswer": "Biometric authentication" },
    { "id": 30, "questionText": "DKIM (DomainKeys Identified Mail), SPF (Sender Policy Framework), and DMARC (Domain-based Message Authentication, Reporting, and Conformance) are three major methods used in:", "options": ["Web browsing", "File sharing", "Email authentication", "Online payments"], "correctAnswer": "Email authentication" },
    { "id": 31, "questionText": "What is a key use of electronic mail in modern world?", "options": ["Playing online games", "Streaming movies", "Communicating with people all over the world for free.", "Buying products online."], "correctAnswer": "Communicating with people all over the world for free." },
    { "id": 32, "questionText": "When creating a multimedia presentation, what type of objects can be included?", "options": ["Only text", "Only images", "Only videos", "Media objects, such as images, text objects, video clips, and audio streams."], "correctAnswer": "Media objects, such as images, text objects, video clips, and audio streams." },
    { "id": 33, "questionText": "In PowerPoint, how do you add a new slide?", "options": ["By clicking 'Save'.", "On the Home tab, click New Slide.", "By selecting 'Print'.", "By going to 'File' menu."], "correctAnswer": "On the Home tab, click New Slide." },
    { "id": 34, "questionText": "What is a 'Note' in PowerPoint used for?", "options": ["To add background music.", "To add speaker notes for the presenter.", "To add animations to slides.", "To change slide transitions."], "correctAnswer": "To add speaker notes for the presenter." },
    { "id": 35, "questionText": "What is the purpose of rehearsing timings for a slideshow?", "options": ["To change the slide order.", "To add new slides.", "To ensure the presentation flows smoothly and stays within a given time limit.", "To insert images."], "correctAnswer": "To ensure the presentation flows smoothly and stays within a given time limit." },
    { "id": 36, "questionText": "Which aspect of PowerPoint allows for a detailed description statement with some voice or Animated or Graphical representation to make it more eye catching and interesting for listeners?", "options": ["Numerical Resources", "Breaking the complexity", "User Ownership", "Point to Point Focus"], "correctAnswer": "Point to Point Focus" },
    { "id": 37, "questionText": "What is the main advantage of Google Mail (Gmail)?", "options": ["It only works on a single platform.", "It functions as an email client connecting to the gmail server using a single organization protocol.", "It has limited storage capacity.", "It is not compatible with other mail protocols."], "correctAnswer": "It functions as an email client connecting to the gmail server using a single organization protocol." },
    { "id": 38, "questionText": "Which of the following is NOT an advantage of PowerPoint mentioned in the source?", "options": ["Diverse multimedia options.", "Numerous resources.", "Breaking the complexity into simpler ways.", "Automatic translation to other languages."], "correctAnswer": "Automatic translation to other languages." },
    { "id": 39, "questionText": "Which folder in email typically stores unwanted or suspicious emails?", "options": ["Inbox", "Sent", "Drafts", "Spam/Junk Mail"], "correctAnswer": "Spam/Junk Mail" },
    { "id": 40, "questionText": "To attach a file to an email, what is the typical icon used?", "options": ["A magnifying glass", "A floppy disk", "A paperclip", "A star"], "correctAnswer": "A paperclip" },
    { "id": 41, "questionText": "What is a good habit for writing an email?", "options": ["Use slang and informal language.", "Use a clear, professional subject line.", "Send without proofreading.", "Leave important details out."], "correctAnswer": "Use a clear, professional subject line." },
    { "id": 42, "questionText": "What does the 'Thesaurus' function provide?", "options": ["Spell check", "Grammar correction", "Synonyms", "Image search"], "correctAnswer": "Synonyms" },
    { "id": 43, "questionText": "To insert text in MS Word, what does the 'Bold' function do?", "options": ["Italicizes the text.", "Underlines the text.", "Changes the font color.", "Makes the text appear thicker and darker."], "correctAnswer": "Makes the text appear thicker and darker." },
    { "id": 44, "questionText": "Which tab is used to insert images in a Word document?", "options": ["Home", "Layout", "Insert", "View"], "correctAnswer": "Insert" },
    { "id": 45, "questionText": "What is the keyboard shortcut for 'Paste'?", "options": ["Ctrl + X", "Ctrl + C", "Ctrl + P", "Ctrl + V"], "correctAnswer": "Ctrl + V" },
    { "id": 46, "questionText": "What is the main purpose of a multimedia presentation?", "options": ["To write long reports.", "To manage spreadsheets.", "To present a set of media objects, such as images, text objects, video clips, and audio streams, in a sequential or interactive manner.", "To create complex algorithms."], "correctAnswer": "To present a set of media objects, such as images, text objects, video clips, and audio streams, in a sequential or interactive manner." },
    { "id": 47, "questionText": "To add notes to a PowerPoint slide, where can you typically find the option?", "options": ["Insert tab", "Design tab", "View menu (specifically 'Notes' button)", "Animations tab"], "correctAnswer": "View menu (specifically 'Notes' button)" },
    { "id": 48, "questionText": "Which of the following describes the ability of PowerPoint to convert the presentation into Video or audio and can be shared on Internet and can be saved to DVD burner?", "options": ["Breaking the complexity", "User Ownership", "Numerous Resources", "Multimedia capability"], "correctAnswer": "Multimedia capability" },
    { "id": 49, "questionText": "What is the purpose of 'Reply to all' in an email?", "options": ["To send a private response to the sender.", "To forward the email to new recipients.", "To send a response to the original sender and all other recipients of the email.", "To delete the email."], "correctAnswer": "To send a response to the original sender and all other recipients of the email." },
    { "id": 50, "questionText": "Email authentication is a technical solution to verify that an email is not forged. In other words, it provides us with a way to authenticate that an email comes from who it claims to be from. Email authentication is most often used to block harmful or fraudulent uses of email such as:", "options": ["Legitimate marketing emails", "Important updates", "Spam", "Personal communication"], "correctAnswer": "Spam" }
  ],
  "Computational Thinking": [
    { "id": 1, "questionText": "What is Computational Thinking (CT)?", "options": ["A method for solving mathematical equations", "A set of problem-solving skills and techniques we use to solve a problem", "A programming language", "A type of computer hardware"], "correctAnswer": "A set of problem-solving skills and techniques we use to solve a problem" },
    { "id": 2, "questionText": "Which of the following is NOT one of the main techniques of Computational Thinking?", "options": ["Decomposition", "Pattern Recognition", "Algorithm Design", "Memorization"], "correctAnswer": "Memorization" },
    { "id": 3, "questionText": "Decomposition in Computational Thinking refers to:", "options": ["Breaking a task or problem into smaller, more manageable parts.", "Finding similarities among problems.", "Developing step-by-step instructions.", "Identifying general rules from observed patterns."], "correctAnswer": "Breaking a task or problem into smaller, more manageable parts." },
    { "id": 4, "questionText": "Pattern Recognition in CT involves:", "options": ["Breaking down complex problems.", "Designing step-by-step solutions.", "Looking for patterns and similarities in problems or solutions.", "Creating abstract models."], "correctAnswer": "Looking for patterns and similarities in problems or solutions." },
    { "id": 5, "questionText": "Generalization and Abstraction in CT refers to:", "options": ["Identifying detailed steps to solve a problem.", "Identifying the details that are relevant to solving the problem and ignoring the details that are not relevant.", "Breaking down a problem into smaller parts.", "Recognizing similarities between problems."], "correctAnswer": "Identifying the details that are relevant to solving the problem and ignoring the details that are not relevant." },
    { "id": 6, "questionText": "Algorithm Design is the process of:", "options": ["Analyzing data patterns.", "Developing instructions to solve similar problems and repeat the process.", "Creating visual representations of data.", "Formulating scientific hypotheses."], "correctAnswer": "Developing instructions to solve similar problems and repeat the process." },
    { "id": 7, "questionText": "Which of the following is a characteristic of an algorithm, meaning it must have clear and unambiguous instructions?", "options": ["Finite-ness", "Feasible", "Clear and Unambiguous", "Language Independent"], "correctAnswer": "Clear and Unambiguous" },
    { "id": 8, "questionText": "An algorithm characteristic which means it must terminate after a finite time is called:", "options": ["Well-Defined Inputs", "Well-Defined Outputs", "Finite-ness", "Language Independent"], "correctAnswer": "Finite-ness" },
    { "id": 9, "questionText": "What does 'Feasible' mean for an algorithm?", "options": ["It must be written in a specific programming language.", "The algorithm must be simple, generic, and practical, so that it can be executed with the available resources.", "It must always produce the same output for the same input.", "It must include an infinite loop."], "correctAnswer": "The algorithm must be simple, generic, and practical, so that it can be executed with the available resources." },
    { "id": 10, "questionText": "An algorithm that uses the simplest approach to solve a problem, often by trying all possible solutions until one is found, is called:", "options": ["Recursive Algorithm", "Sorting Algorithm", "Brute Force Algorithm", "Randomized Algorithm"], "correctAnswer": "Brute Force Algorithm" },
    { "id": 11, "questionText": "Which algorithm type is suitable for arranging a group of data in a particular manner?", "options": ["Brute Force Algorithm", "Recursive Algorithm", "Sorting Algorithm", "Divide and Conquer Algorithm"], "correctAnswer": "Sorting Algorithm" },
    { "id": 12, "questionText": "The Divide and Conquer algorithm works by:", "options": ["Solving the problem directly.", "Breaking a problem into sub-problems, solves a single sub-problem and merges the solutions together to get the final solution.", "Trying all possible solutions.", "Repeatedly calling itself until a base case is reached."], "correctAnswer": "Breaking a problem into sub-problems, solves a single sub-problem and merges the solutions together to get the final solution." },
    { "id": 13, "questionText": "In problem solving, a loop is a sequence of instructions that is executed again and again until a certain condition is true. What type of loop does not have an explicit end?", "options": ["Finite loops", "Repeat loops", "Infinite loops", "Conditional loops"], "correctAnswer": "Infinite loops" },
    { "id": 14, "questionText": "What is the first step in writing an algorithm?", "options": ["Defining the output.", "Determining the process.", "Stating the problem to be solved.", "Checking for errors."], "correctAnswer": "Stating the problem to be solved." },
    { "id": 15, "questionText": "What is the main purpose of a flowchart?", "options": ["To write programming code.", "To store data.", "To graphically represent the steps in an algorithm or process.", "To create complex diagrams."], "correctAnswer": "To graphically represent the steps in an algorithm or process." },
    { "id": 16, "questionText": "Which flowchart symbol represents the start or stop point of a flowchart?", "options": ["Rectangle", "Parallelogram", "Diamond", "Oval / Terminal"], "correctAnswer": "Oval / Terminal" },
    { "id": 17, "questionText": "In a flowchart, what does a rectangle symbol represent?", "options": ["Input/Output", "Decision", "Action / Process", "Start/Stop"], "correctAnswer": "Action / Process" },
    { "id": 18, "questionText": "Which flowchart symbol is used for Input/Output operations?", "options": ["Diamond", "Rectangle", "Parallelogram", "Oval"], "correctAnswer": "Parallelogram" },
    { "id": 19, "questionText": "What does a diamond symbol represent in a flowchart?", "options": ["Process", "Input/Output", "Decision", "Start/Stop"], "correctAnswer": "Decision" },
    { "id": 20, "questionText": "What is a rule for drawing flowcharts regarding flow lines?", "options": ["Flow lines should always cross each other.", "Flow lines coming out of the decision symbol should be labeled properly.", "Flow lines can only go downwards.", "There should only be one flow line from a symbol."], "correctAnswer": "Flow lines coming out of the decision symbol should be labeled properly." },
    { "id": 21, "questionText": "Which of the following is an advantage of flowcharts?", "options": ["Time consuming", "Difficult to understand for people who don't know flowchart symbols", "Easy to make", "Difficult to present complex programs"], "correctAnswer": "Easy to make" },
    { "id": 22, "questionText": "What is the main disadvantage of flowcharts?", "options": ["Easy to understand", "Debugging becomes possible", "Time consuming", "Difficult to present complex programs"], "correctAnswer": "Difficult to present complex programs" },
    { "id": 23, "questionText": "What is the 'Mod' (%) operator used for in an algorithm?", "options": ["Multiplication", "Division", "Addition", "To take remainder/modulus of an Integer"], "correctAnswer": "To take remainder/modulus of an Integer" },
    { "id": 24, "questionText": "How is the efficiency of a solution measured?", "options": ["By the complexity of its design.", "In terms of the number of steps taken by the solution and the memory consumed by the solution.", "By the number of users who understand it.", "By the visual appeal of its flowchart."], "correctAnswer": "In terms of the number of steps taken by the solution and the memory consumed by the solution." },
    { "id": 25, "questionText": "What is the term for breaking down a task or problem into steps or parts?", "options": ["Pattern Recognition", "Generalization", "Algorithm Design", "Decomposition"], "correctAnswer": "Decomposition" },
    { "id": 26, "questionText": "Which principle discovers the similarities that cause these patterns?", "options": ["Decomposition", "Pattern Recognition", "Generalization and Abstraction", "Algorithm Design"], "correctAnswer": "Pattern Recognition" },
    { "id": 27, "questionText": "A set of instructions for solving a problem or accomplishing a task is called:", "options": ["Flowchart", "Algorithm", "Pattern", "Loop"], "correctAnswer": "Algorithm" },
    { "id": 28, "questionText": "What type of algorithm ensures all possible solutions until a required solution is found?", "options": ["Recursive Algorithm", "Brute Force Algorithm", "Searching Algorithm", "Sorting Algorithm"], "correctAnswer": "Brute Force Algorithm" },
    { "id": 29, "questionText": "Which type of algorithm is broken into several sub-parts and called the same procedure again and again?", "options": ["Brute Force Algorithm", "Recursive Algorithm", "Sorting Algorithm", "Searching Algorithm"], "correctAnswer": "Recursive Algorithm" },
    { "id": 30, "questionText": "Which term refers to algorithms that are used for searching elements or groups of elements from a particular data?", "options": ["Sorting algorithms", "Searching algorithms", "Recursive algorithms", "Brute force algorithms"], "correctAnswer": "Searching algorithms" },
    { "id": 31, "questionText": "What is a flow chart?", "options": ["A textual description of a process.", "A programming language.", "A pictorial or symbolic representation of an algorithm.", "A database management system."], "correctAnswer": "A pictorial or symbolic representation of an algorithm." },
    { "id": 32, "questionText": "What is an infinite loop?", "options": ["A loop that runs for a fixed number of iterations.", "A loop that does not have an explicit end, it runs on an infinite time because its condition is not false in any iteration.", "A loop that iterates only once.", "A loop that is always false."], "correctAnswer": "A loop that does not have an explicit end, it runs on an infinite time because its condition is not false in any iteration." },
    { "id": 33, "questionText": "What does the term 'Well-Defined Inputs' mean for an algorithm?", "options": ["The algorithm must produce clear outputs.", "The algorithm must be language independent.", "Inputs of an algorithm should be well-defined.", "The algorithm must terminate in a finite time."], "correctAnswer": "Inputs of an algorithm should be well-defined." },
    { "id": 34, "questionText": "What does 'Well-Defined Outputs' mean for an algorithm?", "options": ["The inputs must be clear.", "The algorithm must be feasible.", "The algorithm must clearly define what output will be and it should be well-defined as well.", "The algorithm must be language independent."], "correctAnswer": "The algorithm must clearly define what output will be and it should be well-defined as well." },
    { "id": 35, "questionText": "The term 'Language Independent' for an algorithm refers to:", "options": ["It must be written in a specific language.", "The algorithm must be programming language-independent.", "It cannot be translated into different languages.", "It is specific to a single operating system."], "correctAnswer": "The algorithm must be programming language-independent." },
    { "id": 36, "questionText": "Which method works by repeatedly breaking down the problem until it is simple enough to be solved directly?", "options": ["Sequence Structure", "Selection Structure", "Divide and Conquer Algorithm", "Lepitaton Structure"], "correctAnswer": "Divide and Conquer Algorithm" },
    { "id": 37, "questionText": "A randomized algorithm helps in:", "options": ["Arranging data in order.", "Breaking a problem into sub-problems.", "Deciding the expected outcome.", "Searching for elements."], "correctAnswer": "Deciding the expected outcome." },
    { "id": 38, "questionText": "In sequence structure, how are steps of an algorithm/program executed?", "options": ["Randomly", "Based on conditions", "In the same order as they are written.", "In loops"], "correctAnswer": "In the same order as they are written." },
    { "id": 39, "questionText": "A conditional statement or set of statements executed only if a condition is true, otherwise another part of the program is executed, describes:", "options": ["Sequence Structure", "Lepitaton Structure", "Selection Structure", "Sorting Algorithm"], "correctAnswer": "Selection Structure" },
    { "id": 40, "questionText": "Computational thinking helps in real life by:", "options": ["Allowing people to make decisions based on emotions.", "Observing in the way people make decisions, do basic arithmetic, and solve problems.", "Limiting problem-solving to computer science.", "Eliminating the need for planning."], "correctAnswer": "Observing in the way people make decisions, do basic arithmetic, and solve problems." },
    { "id": 41, "questionText": "What is the objective of 'The problem that is to be solved by this algorithm' when writing an algorithm?", "options": ["To define the output of the algorithm.", "To state clearly what the algorithm should accomplish.", "To set the constraints for the algorithm.", "To decide the language for the algorithm."], "correctAnswer": "To state clearly what the algorithm should accomplish." },
    { "id": 42, "questionText": "In the algorithm example for finding the largest number from three numbers, what is the first step?", "options": ["Input three unique numbers.", "Check if A is greater than B.", "Print C is largest.", "Start."], "correctAnswer": "Start." },
    { "id": 43, "questionText": "A parallelogram in a flowchart is used for:", "options": ["Process", "Decision", "Input/Output", "Start/End"], "correctAnswer": "Input/Output" },
    { "id": 44, "questionText": "To write an algorithm, 'The output to be expected when the problem is solved' refers to:", "options": ["The conditions for the problem.", "The number of steps in the algorithm.", "The desired result or solution.", "The programming language used."], "correctAnswer": "The desired result or solution." },
    { "id": 45, "questionText": "What is meant by 'Well-Defined Inputs' for an algorithm?", "options": ["The outputs must be clear.", "The algorithm must run quickly.", "Inputs of an algorithm should be well-defined.", "The algorithm must be short."], "correctAnswer": "Inputs of an algorithm should be well-defined." },
    { "id": 46, "questionText": "What does 'Finite loops' imply?", "options": ["Loops that never end.", "Loops that execute for a fixed number of times.", "Loops that are always true.", "Loops that only execute once."], "correctAnswer": "Loops that execute for a fixed number of times." },
    { "id": 47, "questionText": "What is 'Decomposition'?", "options": ["The process of finding patterns.", "Breaking a complex problem into smaller parts.", "Designing an algorithm.", "Identifying general rules."], "correctAnswer": "Breaking a complex problem into smaller parts." },
    { "id": 48, "questionText": "If an algorithm is feasible, it means:", "options": ["It is written in English.", "It has complex logic.", "It can be executed with available resources.", "It never makes errors."], "correctAnswer": "It can be executed with available resources." },
    { "id": 49, "questionText": "What must each step of an algorithm be?", "options": ["Complex and abstract", "Clear and unambiguous", "Recursive", "Finite in duration"], "correctAnswer": "Clear and unambiguous" },
    { "id": 50, "questionText": "What is a 'Brute Force Algorithm'?", "options": ["An algorithm that sorts data.", "An algorithm that divides problems into sub-problems.", "The simplest approach to solve a problem.", "An algorithm that uses randomness."], "correctAnswer": "The simplest approach to solve a problem." }
  ],
  "Programming": [
    { "id": 1, "questionText": "Computers represent everything as numbers. In fact, they can represent everything using the combination of only two numbers that are:", "options": ["1 and 2", "0 and 10", "0 and 1", "-1 and 1"], "correctAnswer": "0 and 1" },
    { "id": 2, "questionText": "The binary number system uses which two digits?", "options": ["1 and 2", "0 and 10", "0 and 1", "1 and 10"], "correctAnswer": "0 and 1" },
    { "id": 3, "questionText": "What is the smallest unit of data in a computer?", "options": ["Byte", "Kilobyte", "Bit", "Megabyte"], "correctAnswer": "Bit" },
    { "id": 4, "questionText": "A Byte is equivalent to how many bits?", "options": ["1 bit", "8 bits", "16 bits", "32 bits"], "correctAnswer": "8 bits" },
    { "id": 5, "questionText": "How many bytes are in one Kilobyte (KB)?", "options": ["8 bytes", "1000 bytes", "1024 bytes", "1,000,000 bytes"], "correctAnswer": "1024 bytes" },
    { "id": 6, "questionText": "A Megabyte (MB) is equal to approximately how many bytes?", "options": ["1024 bytes", "1024 KB", "1,000,000 bytes", "1,048,576 bytes"], "correctAnswer": "1,048,576 bytes" },
    { "id": 7, "questionText": "What is the decimal equivalent of the binary number (100)₂?", "options": ["2", "4", "4", "8"], "correctAnswer": "4" },
    { "id": 8, "questionText": "What is the binary representation of the letter 'A' using ASCII code?", "options": ["0100 0000", "0100 0001", "0100 0001", "0100 0010"], "correctAnswer": "0100 0001" },
    { "id": 9, "questionText": "ASCII code can only store how many characters?", "options": ["64", "128", "256", "512"], "correctAnswer": "128" },
    { "id": 10, "questionText": "The RGB color model uses three primary colors to represent a given color component. What are these colors?", "options": ["Cyan, Magenta, Yellow", "White, Black, Gray", "Red, Green, Blue", "Orange, Purple, Green"], "correctAnswer": "Red, Green, Blue" },
    { "id": 11, "questionText": "What is a 'Sound Wave' in the context of computer science?", "options": ["A visual representation of colors.", "A textual representation of data.", "An analogue signal that can be converted to a waveform for numerical representation.", "A type of binary code."], "correctAnswer": "An analogue signal that can be converted to a waveform for numerical representation." },
    { "id": 12, "questionText": "Which programming software is known for making it easy to create interactive games, animations, and stories using a visual, block-based interface?", "options": ["Python", "Java", "Scratch", "C++"], "correctAnswer": "Scratch" },
    { "id": 13, "questionText": "In Scratch, what is a 'Sprite'?", "options": ["The background of the project.", "A single character by default that is called sprite.", "A script block.", "A variable."], "correctAnswer": "A single character by default that is called sprite." },
    { "id": 14, "questionText": "What are the two main coordinates used to define the position of a Sprite on the Stage in Scratch?", "options": ["Length and Width", "Row and Column", "X and Y coordinates", "Top and Bottom"], "correctAnswer": "X and Y coordinates" },
    { "id": 15, "questionText": "In Scratch, if you press the 'right arrow' key, what direction will the sprite point in?", "options": ["-90 degrees", "0 degrees", "90 degrees", "180 degrees"], "correctAnswer": "90 degrees" },
    { "id": 16, "questionText": "To move a sprite 10 steps in Scratch, which block would you use?", "options": ["change x by 10", "change y by 10", "move 10 steps", "point in direction 10"], "correctAnswer": "move 10 steps" },
    { "id": 17, "questionText": "What is the concept of combining events and coordinates in programming constructs?", "options": ["To complicate user interaction.", "To generate random movements.", "To allow a user to move a sprite or a sprite moves automatically without user intervention.", "To display different sprites."], "correctAnswer": "To allow a user to move a sprite or a sprite moves automatically without user intervention." },
    { "id": 18, "questionText": "To create a new sprite in Scratch, where do you typically click?", "options": ["On the 'Script Area'.", "On the button at the bottom right of your project screen.", "On the 'Stage'.", "On the 'Sprite List'."], "correctAnswer": "On the button at the bottom right of your project screen." },
    { "id": 19, "questionText": "What does the 'Duplicate' option allow you to do in Scratch?", "options": ["Delete a sprite.", "Add a comment to a block.", "Create a copy of a block or sprite.", "Move a sprite."], "correctAnswer": "Create a copy of a block or sprite." },
    { "id": 20, "questionText": "When setting a variable in Scratch, what does 'set [variable name] to [value]' allow you to do?", "options": ["Change the variable's name.", "Assign a value to the variable.", "Create a new variable.", "Delete the variable."], "correctAnswer": "Assign a value to the variable." },
    { "id": 21, "questionText": "In Scratch, to move a sprite using arrow keys (X-Y Method), how do you control movement?", "options": ["By changing the sprite's color.", "By drawing lines on the stage.", "By selecting the sprite you want to move and then adding the following steps to the script area.", "By using random numbers."], "correctAnswer": "By selecting the sprite you want to move and then adding the following steps to the script area." },
    { "id": 22, "questionText": "What happens when the 'up arrow' key is pressed in the X-Y Method for sprite movement?", "options": ["Point in direction 0", "Change x by 10", "Point in direction 180", "Change y by 10"], "correctAnswer": "Change y by 10" },
    { "id": 23, "questionText": "What is the purpose of a 'Loop Method' in programming?", "options": ["To make a program run only once.", "To repeat a code written in it for the number of iteration defined in the start of the loop.", "To stop the program immediately.", "To create conditional statements."], "correctAnswer": "To repeat a code written in it for the number of iteration defined in the start of the loop." },
    { "id": 24, "questionText": "A 'Forever Loop' block in Scratch is used for:", "options": ["Repeating code a specific number of times.", "Repeating code based on a condition.", "Repeating code until a condition is met, if you don't apply a condition it will become an infinite loop.", "Pausing the program."], "correctAnswer": "Repeating code until a condition is met, if you don't apply a condition it will become an infinite loop." },
    { "id": 25, "questionText": "What is the smallest unit of memory your computer can store?", "options": ["Kilobyte", "Byte", "Megabyte", "Bit"], "correctAnswer": "Bit" },
    { "id": 26, "questionText": "Who refined the binary number system in the 17th century?", "options": ["Charles Babbage", "Ada Lovelace", "Gottfried Leibniz", "Alan Turing"], "correctAnswer": "Gottfried Leibniz" },
    { "id": 27, "questionText": "What is the significance of the 'Least Significant Bit' (LSB) and 'Most Significant Bit' (MSB) in a binary number?", "options": ["They indicate the color.", "They determine the speed.", "LSB is the binary number with the lowest value, and MSB is the binary number with the highest value.", "They identify the type of data."], "correctAnswer": "LSB is the binary number with the lowest value, and MSB is the binary number with the highest value." },
    { "id": 28, "questionText": "How can text be converted into a binary number so that it can be processed by the computer?", "options": ["Using RGB codes.", "Using sound waves.", "Using ASCII code.", "Using hexadecimal values."], "correctAnswer": "Using ASCII code." },
    { "id": 29, "questionText": "What is the maximum number of colors that can be represented using 8-bit numbers in the RGB color model?", "options": ["8", "16", "128", "256"], "correctAnswer": "256" },
    { "id": 30, "questionText": "When sampling sound, the 'sampling rate' refers to:", "options": ["The duration of the sound.", "The volume of the sound.", "The number of samples taken every second and that the greater the frequency of the samples, the better the sound quality.", "The pitch of the sound."], "correctAnswer": "The number of samples taken every second and that the greater the frequency of the samples, the better the sound quality." },
    { "id": 31, "questionText": "What is the first step when you open Scratch?", "options": ["Create a new sprite.", "Add a script.", "The following interface is displayed.", "Load a project."], "correctAnswer": "The following interface is displayed." },
    { "id": 32, "questionText": "The white area where you create and interact with your sprites and backgrounds in Scratch is called the:", "options": ["Script Area", "Sprite List", "Stage", "Block Palettes"], "correctAnswer": "Stage" },
    { "id": 33, "questionText": "What is the default direction for a sprite when pointing it to the right in Scratch?", "options": ["-90", "0", "90", "180"], "correctAnswer": "90" },
    { "id": 34, "questionText": "If you want to move a sprite up in Scratch, what direction should you point it in?", "options": ["90", "-90", "0", "180"], "correctAnswer": "0" },
    { "id": 35, "questionText": "When creating a variable in Scratch, which option must you select if the variable is only for the current sprite?", "options": ["For all sprites", "For this sprite only", "Global variable", "Hidden variable"], "correctAnswer": "For this sprite only" },
    { "id": 36, "questionText": "In the 'pick random 1 to 10' block, what does '10' represent?", "options": ["The starting number.", "The maximum possible number.", "The number of random picks.", "The variable name."], "correctAnswer": "The maximum possible number." },
    { "id": 37, "questionText": "Which control block is used to set a timer to a specific value in Scratch?", "options": ["change Timer by", "set Timer to", "stop all", "wait 0.5 seconds"], "correctAnswer": "set Timer to" },
    { "id": 38, "questionText": "The decimal number system is based on which number?", "options": ["0", "1", "2", "10"], "correctAnswer": "10" },
    { "id": 39, "questionText": "What is the decimal equivalent of the binary number 1010?", "options": ["5", "8", "10", "12"], "correctAnswer": "10" },
    { "id": 40, "questionText": "How many bits are used in the ASCII code?", "options": ["6", "7", "8", "16"], "correctAnswer": "7" },
    { "id": 41, "questionText": "What is the decimal representation of the binary code 00000000 for the color Red in RGB?", "options": ["(255,255,255)", "(0,255,0)", "(0,0,0)", "(200,180,120)"], "correctAnswer": "(0,0,0)" },
    { "id": 42, "questionText": "The quality and size of the file is affected by two factors: sample rate and bit rate. The sample rate refers to the number of samples taken every second and that the greater the frequency of the samples, the better the sound quality. The bit rate refers to:", "options": ["The speed of playback.", "The number of bits used to store each sample and that the more bits that are sampled, the better the accuracy of the file but also the greater the file size.", "The volume of the sound.", "The duration of the sound."], "correctAnswer": "The number of bits used to store each sample and that the more bits that are sampled, the better the accuracy of the file but also the greater the file size." },
    { "id": 43, "questionText": "What is the objective of the game in a project-based question involving drawing a cat or a dog?", "options": ["To learn drawing skills.", "To understand complex algorithms.", "To give instructions to complete a simple task.", "To create complex animations."], "correctAnswer": "To give instructions to complete a simple task." },
    { "id": 44, "questionText": "Which Scratch block would you use to change the X coordinate of a sprite?", "options": ["point in direction 90", "move 10 steps", "change y by 10", "change x by 10"], "correctAnswer": "change x by 10" },
    { "id": 45, "questionText": "What does the 'when [key] pressed' event handler do in Scratch?", "options": ["Moves the sprite automatically.", "Changes the sprite's color.", "Initiates an action when a specific key is pressed.", "Creates a new sprite."], "correctAnswer": "Initiates an action when a specific key is pressed." },
    { "id": 46, "questionText": "How can you display the product of two numbers using a variable in Scratch?", "options": ["Using a 'move' block.", "Using a 'pick random' block.", "Using a 'say' block that shows the variable value.", "Using a 'wait' block."], "correctAnswer": "Using a 'say' block that shows the variable value." },
    { "id": 47, "questionText": "What happens if you don't apply a condition to a 'forever loop' block?", "options": ["It stops after 10 seconds.", "It repeats only once.", "It becomes an infinite loop.", "It skips the code inside."], "correctAnswer": "It becomes an infinite loop." },
    { "id": 48, "questionText": "If you want to move a sprite to the left, what direction value should you use?", "options": ["90", "0", "-90", "180"], "correctAnswer": "-90" },
    { "id": 49, "questionText": "In Scratch, what is a 'variable'?", "options": ["A fixed value in a program.", "A named storage location that can hold different values during the program execution.", "A visual block for movement.", "A type of sprite."], "correctAnswer": "A named storage location that can hold different values during the program execution." },
    { "id": 50, "questionText": "What is the smallest unit of data in a computer, represented as a '0' or '1'?", "options": ["Byte", "Kilobyte", "Bit", "Nibble"], "correctAnswer": "Bit" }
  ],
  "Digital Citizenship": [
    { "id": 1, "questionText": "What is the discipline concerned with what is morally good and bad or morally right and wrong?", "options": ["Law", "Ethics", "Sociology", "Psychology"], "correctAnswer": "Ethics" },
    { "id": 2, "questionText": "Which of the following is an example of an ethical issue in a digital environment?", "options": ["Learning a new software", "Working on a project", "Misuse of computer resources", "Using a search engine"], "correctAnswer": "Misuse of computer resources" },
    { "id": 3, "questionText": "According to Aristotle, what is ethics the study of?", "options": ["Human relations in their most perfect form", "Economic principles", "Digital communication", "Technological advancements"], "correctAnswer": "Human relations in their most perfect form" },
    { "id": 4, "questionText": "What is the core principle of being a responsible digital citizen?", "options": ["Being popular online", "Behaving lawfully", "Having many digital friends", "Sharing all personal information"], "correctAnswer": "Behaving lawfully" },
    { "id": 5, "questionText": "Which of these is NOT a property of a good digital citizen?", "options": ["Practice tolerance", "Be informed about the world around you", "Ignore intellectual property", "Be compassionate"], "correctAnswer": "Ignore intellectual property" },
    { "id": 6, "questionText": "What type of scam involves tricking a person into revealing sensitive information to the attacker, often through malicious links?", "options": ["Fake Websites", "Tech Support Scams", "Phishing", "Fake Warning"], "correctAnswer": "Phishing" },
    { "id": 7, "questionText": "What is the purpose of a 'Fake Website' scam?", "options": ["To provide accurate information", "To redirect users to legitimate shopping websites", "To create a site that requires you to enter personal information and misuse it", "To offer free software downloads"], "correctAnswer": "To create a site that requires you to enter personal information and misuse it" },
    { "id": 8, "questionText": "What is the primary objective of 'Tech Support Scams'?", "options": ["To offer legitimate technical assistance", "To ask for money to 'fix' your computer, which is a fake red flag", "To provide free software updates", "To help users improve computer performance"], "correctAnswer": "To ask for money to 'fix' your computer, which is a fake red flag" },
    { "id": 9, "questionText": "According to the U.S Census Bureau, what percentage of all retail sales in 2020 were accounted for by e-commerce?", "options": ["5%", "10%", "14%", "20%"], "correctAnswer": "14%" },
    { "id": 10, "questionText": "What does CRM stand for in the context of internet use in business?", "options": ["Customer Relationship Management", "Centralized Resource Monitoring", "Cloud Resource Management", "Client Requirement Metrics"], "correctAnswer": "Customer Relationship Management" },
    { "id": 11, "questionText": "Which internet platform allows you to collaborate on projects in real time, regardless of where you are located?", "options": ["Google Maps", "Online Gaming", "Google Drive and Microsoft OneDrive", "Social Media"], "correctAnswer": "Google Drive and Microsoft OneDrive" },
    { "id": 12, "questionText": "Which term refers to the use of internet-based social media sites to stay connected with friends, family, colleagues, or customers?", "options": ["E-commerce", "Social networking", "Video conferencing", "Online banking"], "correctAnswer": "Social networking" },
    { "id": 13, "questionText": "Which of the following is NOT an online entertainment resource mentioned?", "options": ["YouTube videos", "Podcasts", "Online shopping", "Music streaming"], "correctAnswer": "Online shopping" },
    { "id": 14, "questionText": "What is 'Copyright'?", "options": ["A type of intellectual property rights that protect original works of an owner", "The right to copy any material", "A form of public domain content", "A license for free distribution"], "correctAnswer": "A type of intellectual property rights that protect original works of an owner" },
    { "id": 15, "questionText": "Which type of plagiarism involves replacing previously submitted work with new content?", "options": ["Global plagiarism", "Paraphrasing plagiarism", "Self-plagiarism", "Patchwork plagiarism"], "correctAnswer": "Self-plagiarism" },
    { "id": 16, "questionText": "What is 'Piracy' in the context of digital content?", "options": ["Legally sharing copyrighted material", "The act of illegally reproducing copyrighted material, such as books, computer programs, and films", "Creating original digital art", "Buying licensed software"], "correctAnswer": "The act of illegally reproducing copyrighted material, such as books, computer programs, and films" },
    { "id": 17, "questionText": "What is 'Media bias'?", "options": ["A news outlet offers opinions to affect the news they report", "Objective reporting of facts", "Balanced presentation of information", "News from a single source"], "correctAnswer": "A news outlet offers opinions to affect the news they report" },
    { "id": 18, "questionText": "Which type of media bias involves presenting an argument as if it has only two sides when there are more?", "options": ["Slant Bias", "Spin Bias", "Sensationalism Bias", "Omission Bias"], "correctAnswer": "Slant Bias" },
    { "id": 19, "questionText": "What does 'Unauthorized access' in misuse of computer resources mean?", "options": ["Accessing public computer terminals", "Accessing computers, computer software, computer data, or networks without authorization", "Using your own computer for personal tasks", "Accessing licensed software"], "correctAnswer": "Accessing computers, computer software, computer data, or networks without authorization" },
    { "id": 20, "questionText": "Which type of misuse of computer resources involves using computer resources for a purpose other than the purpose for which they were intended or authorized?", "options": ["Unauthorized access", "Illegal use", "Improper use", "Interfering with others"], "correctAnswer": "Improper use" },
    { "id": 21, "questionText": "What is 'Privacy' in the digital context?", "options": ["Sharing all your personal data online", "A person's right to have some control over how his or her personal information is used, collected, and shared", "Only protecting your financial information", "Making all your online activities public"], "correctAnswer": "A person's right to have some control over how his or her personal information is used, collected, and shared" },
    { "id": 22, "questionText": "What should you avoid doing when creating strong passwords?", "options": ["Mixing capitalized letters, numbers, and symbols", "Using easily guessable information like your name or birthdate", "Varying your passwords as much as possible", "Making them long"], "correctAnswer": "Using easily guessable information like your name or birthdate" },
    { "id": 23, "questionText": "What is the purpose of using a VPN (Virtual Private Network)?", "options": ["To slow down internet speed", "To add an extra layer of personal privacy on the internet", "To make your online activities publicly visible", "To increase the risk of cyber-attacks"], "correctAnswer": "To add an extra layer of personal privacy on the internet" },
    { "id": 24, "questionText": "How can you avoid clicking on links and attachments in emails from unknown senders?", "options": ["Always click to see what they are", "Trust emails from familiar names only", "Be cautious and verify the sender if unsure", "Forward them to all your contacts"], "correctAnswer": "Be cautious and verify the sender if unsure" },
    { "id": 25, "questionText": "What is the primary danger associated with 'Depression and Anxiety' related to internet use?", "options": ["Increased social networking activity", "Spending too long on social networking sites could adversely affect your mood", "Improved academic performance", "Better physical health"], "correctAnswer": "Spending too long on social networking sites could adversely affect your mood" },
    { "id": 26, "questionText": "What is 'Cyberbullying'?", "options": ["Posting positive comments about others online", "A form of bullying using electronic means", "Sharing educational content", "Creating online support groups"], "correctAnswer": "A form of bullying using electronic means" },
    { "id": 27, "questionText": "What does FOMO stand for?", "options": ["Fear of Missing Out", "Freedom of Online Media", "Friends Online, More Opportunities", "Forgetting Online Memories"], "correctAnswer": "Fear of Missing Out" },
    { "id": 28, "questionText": "What is a consequence of 'Unrealistic Expectations' in the digital age?", "options": ["People share exciting adventures and good news", "Social media forms unrealistic expectations of life and friendships", "Social media leads to increased productivity", "People post only significant content"], "correctAnswer": "Social media forms unrealistic expectations of life and friendships" },
    { "id": 29, "questionText": "What is an 'Unhealthy Sleep Pattern' in the context of digital environment?", "options": ["Getting enough sleep every night", "Spending too much time on digital devices affecting sleep", "Sleeping at regular hours", "Improving sleep quality through meditation"], "correctAnswer": "Spending too much time on digital devices affecting sleep" },
    { "id": 30, "questionText": "According to the summary, what is ethics defined as?", "options": ["The study of human behavior", "The discipline concerned with what is morally good and bad or morally right and wrong", "The art of communication", "The science of data analysis"], "correctAnswer": "The discipline concerned with what is morally good and bad or morally right and wrong" },
    { "id": 31, "questionText": "What is a key aspect of being a responsible digital citizen?", "options": ["Engaging in online conflicts", "Leaving your devices unprotected", "Being a responsible digital citizen means having the online social skills to take part in online community life in an ethical and respectful way", "Spending all your money online"], "correctAnswer": "Being a responsible digital citizen means having the online social skills to take part in online community life in an ethical and respectful way" },
    { "id": 32, "questionText": "What does phishing aim to do?", "options": ["Send you a malicious link to trick a person into revealing sensitive information", "Help you secure your online accounts", "Provide legitimate software updates", "Offer online discounts"], "correctAnswer": "Send you a malicious link to trick a person into revealing sensitive information" },
    { "id": 33, "questionText": "What benefit does the Internet provide regarding useful data and information?", "options": ["It makes data harder to find", "It makes data inaccessible", "It makes data easy to use, and simple", "It only provides entertainment"], "correctAnswer": "It makes data easy to use, and simple" },
    { "id": 34, "questionText": "What percentage of all retail sales in the U.S. Census Bureau 2020 E-commerce accounted for?", "options": ["10 percent", "14 percent", "20 percent", "25 percent"], "correctAnswer": "14 percent" },
    { "id": 35, "questionText": "What is CRM (Client Relationship Management) defined as?", "options": ["Software that manages client complaints", "Software that helps businesses better serve their customers, increase purchases and find new customers", "A tool for market research", "A system for tracking employee performance"], "correctAnswer": "Software that helps businesses better serve their customers, increase purchases and find new customers" },
    { "id": 36, "questionText": "What does the term 'social networking' refer to?", "options": ["The use of online gaming platforms", "The use of internet-based social media sites to stay connected with friends, family, colleagues, or customers", "The process of creating professional websites", "The act of sending emails"], "correctAnswer": "The use of internet-based social media sites to stay connected with friends, family, colleagues, or customers" },
    { "id": 37, "questionText": "What right does copyright protect?", "options": ["The right to freely copy and distribute works", "Intellectual property rights that protect original works of an owner", "The right to modify any digital content", "The right to resell copyrighted material"], "correctAnswer": "Intellectual property rights that protect original works of an owner" },
    { "id": 38, "questionText": "What is plagiarism defined as?", "options": ["Presenting other’s work or ideas as your own, with or without consent", "Collaborating on projects", "Citing all sources correctly", "Conducting independent research"], "correctAnswer": "Presenting other’s work or ideas as your own, with or without consent" },
    { "id": 39, "questionText": "What is piracy?", "options": ["The act of legally sharing copyrighted material", "The act of illegally reproducing copyrighted material, such as books, computer programs, and films", "Digital rights management", "Open-source software development"], "correctAnswer": "The act of illegally reproducing copyrighted material, such as books, computer programs, and films" },
    { "id": 40, "questionText": "How does a news outlet typically exercise 'media bias'?", "options": ["By reporting facts objectively", "By allowing opinions to affect the news they report", "By providing multiple perspectives", "By focusing only on local news"], "correctAnswer": "By allowing opinions to affect the news they report" },
    { "id": 41, "questionText": "What is a consequence of spending too long on social networking sites according to the source?", "options": ["Improved mood", "Adverse affect on your mood", "Increased productivity", "Enhanced social connections"], "correctAnswer": "Adverse affect on your mood" },
    { "id": 42, "questionText": "What happens to devices left unprotected online?", "options": ["They can run as small as a slower computer", "They are fully secure", "They become faster", "They automatically update software"], "correctAnswer": "They can run as small as a slower computer" },
    { "id": 43, "questionText": "What is the main goal of 'Protecting your privacy' online?", "options": ["To share as much personal information as possible", "To keep privacy settings up to date on social media sites", "To make all information publicly available", "To ignore privacy settings"], "correctAnswer": "To keep privacy settings up to date on social media sites" },
    { "id": 44, "questionText": "Which type of plagiarism involves paraphrasing something else's ideas and presenting them as if they were your own original thoughts?", "options": ["Global plagiarism", "Paraphrasing plagiarism", "Patchwork plagiarism", "Self-plagiarism"], "correctAnswer": "Paraphrasing plagiarism" },
    { "id": 45, "questionText": "What does 'Unlawful use' mean in the context of computer resources?", "options": ["Using licensed software", "Violating any software licensing or copyright", "Using freeware programs", "Accessing public domain information"], "correctAnswer": "Violating any software licensing or copyright" },
    { "id": 46, "questionText": "How can you make it clear that information is not from your sources in your response? [Instruction from prompt]", "options": ["By not mentioning sources", "By stating it is not from your sources and suggesting independent verification", "By citing external websites", "By using personal opinions"], "correctAnswer": "By stating it is not from your sources and suggesting independent verification" },
    { "id": 47, "questionText": "What should a good digital citizen do regarding their reputation online?", "options": ["Ignore it", "Protect it by safeguarding privacy and content", "Let others manage it", "Only care about offline reputation"], "correctAnswer": "Protect it by safeguarding privacy and content" },
    { "id": 48, "questionText": "Which social media platform is mentioned as a place where cyberbullying occurs?", "options": ["LinkedIn", "Instagram", "Twitter", "Facebook"], "correctAnswer": "Facebook" },
    { "id": 49, "questionText": "What is the general advice for using social media regarding personal information?", "options": ["Share everything freely", "Be careful what you share online", "Only share with close friends", "Only share during specific hours"], "correctAnswer": "Be careful what you share online" },
    { "id": 50, "questionText": "What is one of the key concepts of 'Digital Citizenship'?", "options": ["Using digital devices for entertainment only", "Participating in online commerce", "Understanding ethical issues in a digital environment", "Developing programming skills"] },
    { "id": 51, "questionText": "What is a 'Good Digital Citizen'? a) Someone who never uses the internet. b) Someone who always agrees with others online. c) Someone who respects for yourself and other people and is important in all relationships. d) Someone who shares all personal information online.", "correctAnswer": "Someone who respects for yourself and other people and is important in all relationships." }
  ],
  "Entrepreneurship in Digital Age": [
    { "id": 1, "questionText": "What is a 'business plan'?", "options": ["A marketing strategy", "An essential written document that provides a detailed description and a complete overview of the company's future", "A financial statement", "A project timeline"], "correctAnswer": "An essential written document that provides a detailed description and a complete overview of the company's future" },
    { "id": 2, "questionText": "Which of the following is NOT listed as a key section of a business plan?", "options": ["Executive summary", "Competitor analysis", "Personal hobbies", "Marketing plan"], "correctAnswer": "Personal hobbies" },
    { "id": 3, "questionText": "What does the 'Executive summary' section of a business plan include?", "options": ["Detailed financial projections", "A table of contents, company background, market opportunity, management overviews, competitive advantages, and financial highlights", "Employee list", "Product design specifications"], "correctAnswer": "A table of contents, company background, market opportunity, management overviews, competitive advantages, and financial highlights" },
    { "id": 4, "questionText": "The 'Business description and structure' section of a business plan explains:", "options": ["Only the financial projections.", "In detail why you are in business and what products are you selling.", "The complete marketing plan.", "Competitor analysis."], "correctAnswer": "In detail why you are in business and what products are you selling." },
    { "id": 5, "questionText": "What does 'Competitor Analysis' involve in a business plan?", "options": ["Analyzing your own strengths.", "For any business to initiate in a market, they research should always be done on the competitors of that business.", "Developing new products.", "Setting pricing strategies."], "correctAnswer": "For any business to initiate in a market, they research should always be done on the competitors of that business." },
    { "id": 6, "questionText": "What does 'Development plan of your products' in a business plan outline?", "options": ["Financial forecasts.", "Marketing strategies.", "How the plan will be executed and implemented.", "Organizational structure."], "correctAnswer": "How the plan will be executed and implemented." },
    { "id": 7, "questionText": "What does 'Marketing research and strategies' section of a business plan elaborate on?", "options": ["Employee training plans.", "Your market analysis and explain your marketing strategy, including sales forecasts, deadlines and milestones, advertising, public relations to formulate a successful business plan.", "Production process.", "Legal framework."], "correctAnswer": "Your market analysis and explain your marketing strategy, including sales forecasts, deadlines and milestones, advertising, public relations to formulate a successful business plan." },
    { "id": 8, "questionText": "'Management and personnel' in a business plan provides:", "options": ["Financial statements.", "Bios of your company executives and managers and explain how their expertise will help you meet business goals.", "Marketing campaigns.", "Product specifications."], "correctAnswer": "Bios of your company executives and managers and explain how their expertise will help you meet business goals." },
    { "id": 9, "questionText": "What are 'Financial documents' in a business plan used for?", "options": ["Describing the products.", "Providing the numbers and digits that back up everything you explained in your organizational and marketing sections.", "Outlining company values.", "Planning future events."], "correctAnswer": "Providing the numbers and digits that back up everything you explained in your organizational and marketing sections." },
    { "id": 10, "questionText": "Promotion in the digital age can be defined as:", "options": ["Only sales activities.", "The creation of new products.", "The entire set of activities, which communicates the product, brand or service to the user.", "Managing inventory."], "correctAnswer": "The entire set of activities, which communicates the product, brand or service to the user." },
    { "id": 11, "questionText": "Value proposition in marketing is a concise statement of the benefits that a company is delivering to customers who buy its products or services. Which of the following is a key aspect of a strong value proposition?", "options": ["Being the cheapest product.", "Having the most features.", "Clearly communicating unique value to customers.", "Being available everywhere."], "correctAnswer": "Clearly communicating unique value to customers." },
    { "id": 12, "questionText": "What does 'Quality assurance' ensure in a business?", "options": ["Fast production.", "Low costs.", "A process that helps a business adheres to its product's quality standards set by the company or its industry.", "Aggressive marketing."], "correctAnswer": "A process that helps a business adheres to its product's quality standards set by the company or its industry." },
    { "id": 13, "questionText": "Why is 'Project Management' important?", "options": ["To avoid planning.", "To allow projects to run indefinitely.", "It helps to perceive project management, planning, reporting, tracking, and the importance of project management.", "To focus only on sales."], "correctAnswer": "It helps to perceive project management, planning, reporting, tracking, and the importance of project management." },
    { "id": 14, "questionText": "What is 'Media literacy'?", "options": ["The ability to create media content.", "The ability to ignore media messages.", "Enables the populace to understand and contribute to public discourse, and, eventually make sound decisions when electing their leaders.", "The ability to program."], "correctAnswer": "Enables the populace to understand and contribute to public discourse, and, eventually make sound decisions when electing their leaders." },
    { "id": 15, "questionText": "What is the voluntary transfer of money, equivalent, or other valuable items from one person to another in exchange for goods or services received or to meet a legal obligation?", "options": ["Transaction", "Credit", "Debit", "Payments"], "correctAnswer": "Payments" },
    { "id": 16, "questionText": "A transaction is a completed agreement between a buyer and a seller to exchange goods, services, or financial assets in return for money. Which of the following is NOT a type of transaction?", "options": ["Purchase", "Sale", "Refund", "Donation (Donation is a transfer but not necessarily an exchange for goods/services for money)"], "correctAnswer": "Donation (Donation is a transfer but not necessarily an exchange for goods/services for money)" },
    { "id": 17, "questionText": "Which digital marketing tool is considered the 'most important'?", "options": ["Email marketing", "Content marketing", "Social media marketing", "Web advertising"], "correctAnswer": "Social media marketing" },
    { "id": 18, "questionText": "What is 'Search Engine Optimization (SEO)'?", "options": ["Creating social media posts.", "Running paid advertisements.", "A digital marketing technique that involves creating more traffic to a website by making sure that the website appears higher up in the results of a search engine like Google.", "Sending email newsletters."], "correctAnswer": "A digital marketing technique that involves creating more traffic to a website by making sure that the website appears higher up in the results of a search engine like Google." },
    { "id": 19, "questionText": "What is 'Email marketing'?", "options": ["Sending physical mail to customers.", "A great marketing technique to get customers to return to a brand and purchase new products.", "Placing ads on websites.", "Creating social media campaigns."], "correctAnswer": "A great marketing technique to get customers to return to a brand and purchase new products." },
    { "id": 20, "questionText": "Content Marketing is described as:", "options": ["Only creating blog posts.", "Only creating videos.", "Creating valuable and relevant content consistently on platforms.", "Only posting on social media."], "correctAnswer": "Creating valuable and relevant content consistently on platforms." },
    { "id": 21, "questionText": "Video marketing is described as:", "options": ["Selling videos online.", "Video marketing works in coherence with content marketing and is also a popular technique in digital marketing because of the easy access to videos that technology has provided.", "Creating still images for advertisements.", "Text-based advertisements."], "correctAnswer": "Video marketing works in coherence with content marketing and is also a popular technique in digital marketing because of the easy access to videos that technology has provided." },
    { "id": 22, "questionText": "What is 'Web advertising'?", "options": ["Advertising in newspapers.", "Brands can get themselves more effective marketing and advertising by creating clickable advertisements to put on popular websites.", "Radio advertisements.", "Television commercials."], "correctAnswer": "Brands can get themselves more effective marketing and advertising by creating clickable advertisements to put on popular websites." },
    { "id": 23, "questionText": "Affiliate advertising involves:", "options": ["Direct selling to customers.", "A brand pays to have a valuable spokesperson with a large audience, usually a blogger or social media influencer, to post about their company so that a company can increase its circulation.", "Running an in-house marketing team.", "Cold calling customers."], "correctAnswer": "A brand pays to have a valuable spokesperson with a large audience, usually a blogger or social media influencer, to post about their company so that a company can increase its circulation." },
    { "id": 24, "questionText": "What is the goal of 'Overall personalization' in digital marketing?", "options": ["To show the same content to everyone.", "Creating a unique style can make people believe whether a company is successful or not.", "To automate all marketing efforts.", "To minimize customer interaction."], "correctAnswer": "Creating a unique style can make people believe whether a company is successful or not." },
    { "id": 25, "questionText": "'Creating an App' involves:", "options": ["Designing websites.", "Creating an app for a brand can give viewers an accessible means of communication and show.", "Making physical products.", "Running social media campaigns."], "correctAnswer": "Creating an app for a brand can give viewers an accessible means of communication and show." },
    { "id": 26, "questionText": "Which of the following is a component of the SEO Pyramid?", "options": ["Offline advertising", "Print media", "Keyword Research & Targeting", "Direct mail campaigns"], "correctAnswer": "Keyword Research & Targeting" },
    { "id": 27, "questionText": "Twitter emerged from the podcasting venture Odeo, which was founded in 2005. What kind of content did Odeo initially produce?", "options": ["Video blogs", "Digital media application iTunes", "Text messages", "Photo sharing"], "correctAnswer": "Digital media application iTunes" },
    { "id": 28, "questionText": "Snapchat was founded by who?", "options": ["Mark Zuckerberg", "Jack Dorsey", "Evan Spiegel and Bobby Murphy", "Bill Gates"], "correctAnswer": "Evan Spiegel and Bobby Murphy" },
    { "id": 29, "questionText": "What does the 'Technology as an enabler in entrepreneurship' concept suggest?", "options": ["Technology limits entrepreneurship.", "Individuals, entrepreneurship enablers are those who make it possible for entrepreneurs to emerge and grow in the first place.", "Technology is only for large businesses.", "Technology reduces the need for innovation."], "correctAnswer": "Individuals, entrepreneurship enablers are those who make it possible for entrepreneurs to emerge and grow in the first place." },
    { "id": 30, "questionText": "Which of the following is NOT a common example of successful digital platforms used for entrepreneurship?", "options": ["Facebook", "Twitter", "LinkedIn", "Traditional newspapers"], "correctAnswer": "Traditional newspapers" },
    { "id": 31, "questionText": "What is a 'Knowledge platform' example?", "options": ["Facebook", "Airbnb", "Quora or Reddit", "YouTube"], "correctAnswer": "Quora or Reddit" },
    { "id": 32, "questionText": "Which digital platform is service-oriented?", "options": ["YouTube", "Reddit", "Airbnb", "LinkedIn"], "correctAnswer": "Airbnb" },
    { "id": 33, "questionText": "What is an example of an E-commerce platform?", "options": ["Facebook", "Twitter", "Alibaba", "Quora"], "correctAnswer": "Alibaba" },
    { "id": 34, "questionText": "In the 'Types of Business Models', what category does Facebook belong to?", "options": ["Search Platforms", "Sharing Economy Platforms", "Social Media Platforms", "Development Platforms"], "correctAnswer": "Social Media Platforms" },
    { "id": 35, "questionText": "Booking Aggregators (e.g., Booking.com, Expedia, and Pagoda) fall under which type of business model?", "options": ["Retail Platforms", "Payment Platforms", "Content & Review Platforms", "Social Media Platforms"], "correctAnswer": "Content & Review Platforms" },
    { "id": 36, "questionText": "What does a 'business description' in a business plan clarify?", "options": ["Only the team members.", "The future financial projections.", "A complete overview of the company's future.", "The marketing budget."], "correctAnswer": "A complete overview of the company's future." },
    { "id": 37, "questionText": "What is a primary function of 'financial planning and factors' in a business plan?", "options": ["To describe daily operations.", "To outline marketing strategies.", "To present the monetary aspects and requirements of the business.", "To detail product development."], "correctAnswer": "To present the monetary aspects and requirements of the business." },
    { "id": 38, "questionText": "The term 'Value proposition' in marketing refers to:", "options": ["The pricing strategy.", "The product features.", "The concise statement of the benefits that a company is delivering to its customers.", "The advertising campaign."], "correctAnswer": "The concise statement of the benefits that a company is delivering to its customers." },
    { "id": 39, "questionText": "Which of the following describes 'Project management'?", "options": ["Quality assurance", "Media literacy", "The process of planning, executing, and closing a project.", "Financial document"], "correctAnswer": "The process of planning, executing, and closing a project." },
    { "id": 40, "questionText": "What is the key role of 'digital platforms' in entrepreneurship?", "options": ["To limit market access.", "To increase physical infrastructure.", "To provide a collection of business and/or technology capabilities that other products or services consume to deliver their own business capabilities.", "To reduce innovation."], "correctAnswer": "To provide a collection of business and/or technology capabilities that other products or services consume to deliver their own business capabilities." },
    { "id": 41, "questionText": "What is 'Crowdsourcing & Crowdfunding'?", "options": ["A type of social media.", "A service-oriented platform.", "A platform that allows individuals or organizations to obtain resources (e.g., funding, ideas) from a large, undefined group of people.", "An e-commerce platform."], "correctAnswer": "A platform that allows individuals or organizations to obtain resources (e.g., funding, ideas) from a large, undefined group of people." },
    { "id": 42, "questionText": "According to the sources, why is it important to research market important when planning to set up a business?", "options": ["To determine employee salaries.", "To decide the company's name.", "To understand the target audience and competitive landscape, which helps in making informed decisions about product development, pricing, and marketing strategies.", "To choose office location."], "correctAnswer": "To understand the target audience and competitive landscape, which helps in making informed decisions about product development, pricing, and marketing strategies." },
    { "id": 43, "questionText": "What is 'Twitter' primarily known for?", "options": ["Long-form articles and journals.", "E-commerce transactions.", "A micro-blogging service where users send short messages.", "Video streaming."], "correctAnswer": "A micro-blogging service where users send short messages." },
    { "id": 44, "questionText": "What is a 'blog'?", "options": ["A platform for sending private messages.", "A social media network focused on images.", "An online journal or informational website displaying information in reverse chronological order.", "A software for editing videos."], "correctAnswer": "An online journal or informational website displaying information in reverse chronological order." },
    { "id": 45, "questionText": "What is the significance of the 'ICT AS ENABLER' concept in entrepreneurship?", "options": ["It creates constraints for businesses.", "It provides opportunities for businesses.", "It only focuses on existing businesses.", "It is irrelevant to new business processes."], "correctAnswer": "It provides opportunities for businesses." },
    { "id": 46, "questionText": "Which digital platform facilitates person-to-person sharing of assets and resources (e.g., cars and bicycles)?", "options": ["Communication Platforms", "Retail Platforms", "Sharing Economy Platforms", "Development Platforms"], "correctAnswer": "Sharing Economy Platforms" },
    { "id": 47, "questionText": "'Development Platforms' are exemplified by:", "options": ["Google, Bing, Yahoo.", "Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn.", "e.g appstores and, gaming consoles", "eBay, Amazon."], "correctAnswer": "e.g appstores and, gaming consoles" },
    { "id": 48, "questionText": "Which financial metric is crucial for analyzing the monetary success and health of a business?", "options": ["Marketing spend.", "Employee satisfaction.", "Financial information, planning and factors.", "Customer reviews."], "correctAnswer": "Financial information, planning and factors." },
    { "id": 49, "questionText": "What is a 'Competitor Analysis'?", "options": ["Business description.", "Executive summary.", "An assessment of the strengths and weaknesses of current and potential competitors.", "Project management."], "correctAnswer": "An assessment of the strengths and weaknesses of current and potential competitors." },
    { "id": 50, "questionText": "What is the importance of 'Quality Assurance'?", "options": ["It only focuses on customer service.", "It ensures that products and services meet certain quality standards.", "It is solely about marketing.", "It manages employee performance."], "correctAnswer": "It ensures that products and services meet certain quality standards." }
]
}